writerswrite.co.za 2019-04-18

# Privacy Policy - Writers Write

#### Who we are

Our website address is: https://writerswrite.co.za

Please click here to read more about what we do: [About Writers Write](https://writerswrite.co.za/company/)

#### What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymised string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

#### Courses

If you sign up for a course…

At checkout, we will collect your name, email address, username, and password. This information is used to setup your account for our site. If you are redirected to an offsite payment gateway to complete your payment, we may store this information in a temporary session variable to setup your account when you return to our site.

When logged in, we use cookies to track some of your activity on our site including logins, visits, and page views.

#### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

#### Contact forms

**We collect your email address in order to:**

  1. Subscribe you to our [Daily Writing Links](https://writerswrite.co.za/join-our-newsletter/)
  2. Send information, respond to enquiries, and/or other requests or questions
  3. Process orders and to send information and updates pertaining to orders.

**We agree to:**

  1. Not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.
  2. Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.
  3. Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.
  4. Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
  5. Honour opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.
  6. Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

If you would like to unsubscribe from receiving emails, you can email us at [news@writerswrite.co.za](mailto:news@writerswrite.co.za) with UNSUBSCRIBE in the subject line. We will remove you from all mailing lists.

#### Cookies

Our website requires cookies to operate. They allow us to use things like social media plugins and to allow you to use our online courses.

Cookies are also use for analytic purposes to tell us, for example, when the busiest time for our website is.

Be aware that some cookies are necessary for the operation of the site however you can opt out of allowing Google Analytics if it concerns you.

Cookies store some information in your browser, your login details for example. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

#### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

#### Analytics

We use Google Analytics on our site. You can opt-out of tracking.

#### Google Ads

We don’t do this yet, but we will update this section if we do.

Google’s advertising requirements may use your Google user profile to target their adverts at you, this is beyond our control. You can edit your profile settings in your [google account](https://accounts.google.com/signin/v2/sl/pwd?service=accountsettings&passive=1209600&osid=1&continue=https%3A%2F%2Fmyaccount.google.com%2Femail&followup=https%3A%2F%2Fmyaccount.google.com%2Femail&authuser=0&csig=AF-SEnat4XF4cQyx2q9H%3A1530442198&flowName=GlifWebSignIn&flowEntry=ServiceLogin).

Manage the ads you see with Ad Settings or with [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices).

#### Who we share your data with

We do not share your data with anybody. We use certain third party services. Please follow the links to read their Privacy Policies.

**Payment processors** : We have no access to your credit card information. Payments are processed through [PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/en/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) and iVeri. They are not processed on this site. Please make sure you are familiar with their Privacy Policies

**Shop** : We use [Woocommerce](https://woocommerce.com/privacy-policy/)

**Newsletter** : We send emails via [Mailchimp](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/).

**Social Media Platforms** : If you sign-up or login using a social media platform you grant them access to your information. You can manage this from within the social media platform. We use the [Ultimate Social Media PLUS](https://www.ultimatelysocial.com/gdpr/).

[**Wordfence**](https://www.wordfence.com/privacy-policy/): Keeps our site safe.

**Book Sales** : We are an Amazon affiliate. Please check their [privacy policy](https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/data-privacy-faq/).

#### How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognise and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

#### What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

#### Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service. But you data is checked by us in person and not sent anywhere.

#### General

#### Your contact information

If you sign up for an online course, we store your username and e-mail address on our server.

#### How we protect your data

Your data is stored on our secure server. We have taken a number of precaution to protect your data. Such as not storing any data that could be used to impersonate you. We do not record any data used while making payments other than your name and what you were buying.

Our server is kept up-to-date and protected by our IT team as well as third party security partners.

#### What third parties we receive data from

We receive no data other than what you give us you and data recorded by Google Analitics.

#### What automated decision making and/or profiling we do with user data

We believe that all decisions about data should be made by a person not a computer and as such we do not use automated profiling. All decisions regarding behaviour are reviewed by us manually.
